<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Last of the Romans</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/" />
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/atom.xml" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008-01-27://1</id>
    <updated>2008-08-28T15:22:40Z</updated>
    <subtitle>A socioeconomic and political view of the modern world with an admitted classicist bias.</subtitle>
    <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Open Source 4.1</generator>

<entry>
    <title>Highlights from Joe Biden&apos;s Speech at the DNC</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2008/08/highlights-from-joe-bidens-spe.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008://1.293</id>

    <published>2008-08-28T14:58:19Z</published>
    <updated>2008-08-28T15:22:40Z</updated>

    <summary>I&apos;ve always been a big Joe Biden supporter. He was my candidate during the primaries this year so it goes without saying how excited I am to see him on the ticket with Obama. Here are some quotes from his...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="America" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><a href="http://lastoftheromans.org/blather/archives/41713769.html" onclick="window.open('http://lastoftheromans.org/blather/archives/41713769.html','popup','width=500,height=378,scrollbars=no,resizable=no,toolbar=no,directories=no,location=no,menubar=no,status=no,left=0,top=0'); return false"><img src="http://lastoftheromans.org/blather/archives/41713769-thumb-150x113.jpg" alt="41713769.jpg" class="mt-image-left" style="margin: 0pt 20px 20px 0pt; float: left;" width="150" height="113" /></a></span>I've always been a big Joe Biden supporter. He was my candidate during the primaries this year so it goes without saying how excited I am to see him on the ticket with Obama. Here are some quotes from his speech last night that I thought were spot-on:<br /><br />"On the most important national security issues of our time, John McCain has been wrong and Barack Obama has been proven right." <br /><br />"My mother's creed is the American creed: No one is better than you. Everyone is your equal, and everyone is equal to you."<br /><br />"Even today, as oil companies post the biggest profits in history,
nearly $500 billion in the last five years, John wants to give them
another $4 billion in tax breaks. That's not change. That's the same."<br /><br />"And when he says he'll continue to spend $10 billion a month, when the
Iraqis have a surplus of nearly $80 billion, that's not change. That's
more of the same."<br /><br />"Should you trust the judgment of John McCain, when he said only
three years ago, "Afghanistan, we don't read about it anymore in papers
because it succeeded"?<p> Or should you believe Barack Obama who said a year ago, "We need to send two more combat battalions to Afghanistan"?</p><p>
The fact of the matter is, al Qaeda and the Taliban, the people who
actually attacked us on 9/11, they've regrouped in the mountains
between Afghanistan and Pakistan and they are plotting new attacks. And
the chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff has echoed Barack's call for
more troops.</p><p> John McCain was wrong, and Barack Obama was right."</p><p>"Folks, remember when the world used to trust us, when they looked to us
for leadership? With Barack Obama as our president, they'll look at us
again, they'll trust us again, and we'll be able to lead again."</p><br /> <div><br /></div>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Battle of Manzikert: redux</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2008/08/battle-of-manzikert-redux.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008://1.292</id>

    <published>2008-08-26T18:48:10Z</published>
    <updated>2008-08-26T19:20:49Z</updated>

    <summary> It is fitting that Hillary Clinton, after a bitter and divisive primary battle with Barack Obama, should give her speech at the Democratic National Convention in Denver, on the 937th anniversary of the Battle of Manzikert. Manzikert was an...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="America" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>
<p><a onclick="window.open('http://lastoftheromans.org/blather/archives/hilary-clinton.html','popup','width=499,height=360,scrollbars=no,resizable=no,toolbar=no,directories=no,location=no,menubar=no,status=no,left=0,top=0'); return false" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/blather/archives/hilary-clinton.html"><img class="mt-image-left" style="FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 20px 20px 0px" height="108" alt="hilary-clinton.jpg" src="http://lastoftheromans.org/blather/archives/hilary-clinton-thumb-150x108.jpg" width="150" /></a>It is fitting that Hillary Clinton, after a bitter and divisive primary battle with Barack Obama, should give her speech at the Democratic National Convention in Denver, on the 937th anniversary of the Battle of Manzikert.</p>
<p>Manzikert was an important trading center in ancient Armenia, which at the time was a Byzantine vassal state. The Turks, recent immigrants from Central Asia, had begun moving into lands controlled by the Roman Empire and its successor in the East, the Byzantine Empire. The Turks had no interest in being good neighbors. Motivated by Islam, they ransacked Christian Armenia and eastern Asia Minor. </p>
<p>The Byzantines, for many years medieval Europe's most powerful and wealthy state, had become severely weakened by a series of utterly inept leaders with no military experience - and an addiction to civil strife and palace infighting.</p>
<p>Events came to fruition on a warm August day in 1071 - the Turks recently conquered the Armenian capital Ani and were poised to overrun Asia Minor.</p>
<p>Emperor Romanus Diogenes set off with an army of 70,000 towards the East. With him, as co-regent, was Andronikos Doukas, his chief (and quite bitter) rival. </p>
<p>As the battle began, the Turks approached in a crescent formation, attempting to draw the Byzantines into the center to be flanked on both sides by archers. The Byzantines held off the main attack and even succeeded to seize Sultan Alp Arslan's camp by the afternoon. The Turkish cavalry, however, in classic steppe form, was harassing Byzantine forces in hit and run attacks. The Emperor, realizing the exposure of his troops, ordered his forces to pull back into a more defensive posture. Doukas deliberately ignored the Emperor's command, effectively splitting the Byzantine force in two. The Turks saw the confusion and chaos among the Byzantine troops and pressed a full attack, breaking the lines and capturing Emperor Romanos Diogenes himself. Some portion of the Byzantine army managed to escape, including much of its leadership, save for Diogenes.</p>
<p>While Diogenes was in captivity, his rival Doukas, returned to Constantinople and proclaimed himself Emperor. </p>
<p>Examined&nbsp;in the greater historical context of constant civil strife, within 100 years the Turks had conquered, both ethnically and religiously, nearly all of Asia Minor. Doukas' legacy is best remembered as opening the door for the&nbsp;final destruction of Graeco-Roman civilization in Europe - as well as the forced conversion&nbsp;to Islam or&nbsp;explusion of Greeks from what is now known as Turkey.</p>
<p>Clinton faces a deep personal choice tonight. Does she throw the greater good aside in her pursuit of "the purple" or does she hold ranks and keep as one for the victory of a party rival?</p></p>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Attack of the (Mac) Clones?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2008/04/attack-of-the-mac-clones.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008://1.291</id>

    <published>2008-04-16T13:58:38Z</published>
    <updated>2008-04-16T13:59:02Z</updated>

    <summary> A Miami-based company announced recently a new product called &quot;Open Computer&quot; with which they say you can install the Mac operating system, effectively turning it into a &quot;Mac-compatible.&quot;With a $399 price tag for a pretty hefty set of components,...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Technology" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="technology" label="technology" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[
    

        
A Miami-based company announced recently a new product called "Open
Computer" with which they say you can install the Mac operating system,
effectively turning it into a "Mac-compatible."<br /><br />With
a $399 price tag for a pretty hefty set of components, it is about half
the price of Apple's cheapest (and underpowered) Mac, the Mac Mini. <br /><br />The
emergency of Open Computer is causing quite a stir among the geek
crowd; Macs, as opposed to PCs (nee IBM-Compatibles) are only available
through Apple Inc., Apple software running on Apple hardware. Many in
the industry blame Apple's current 10% market share on its failure to
license its software to hardware manufacturers in the 1980s. Microsoft,
on the other hand, was just a software company selling its operating
system (Windows) to anyone who wanted to buy it. This allowed for a
freer market, so to speak, on the PC side, and the rest is history.<br /><br />The
concept of Apple clones is not without precedent. In the 1990s Apple
licensed its software for a two or three year period and several Mac
clone companies emerged, notably Power Computing and UMax. I actually
had a UMax c160 for a period of time. When Steve Jobs returned to Apple
in 1999, however, he put the kibosh on the clone business.<br /><br />Being
a longtime Mac fanatic, the 1990s were a tough decade. Apple was
bottoming out both in market share and in share price. For a while
there were rumors the company was getting bought by IBM or Motorola.
Mac software was disappearing from store shelves, some stores stopped
selling Mac software entirely. It looked like the end of the line. I
was frustrated that Apple wouldn't change its tune and "deregulate" its
licensing philosophy, given the superiority of its platform to Windows.<br /><br />The
2000s have been a completely different story for Apple. Steve Jobs
returned and effectively innovated Apple back into the spotlight
through the release of excellent products, expanding from traditional
computers to consumer electronics and music.<br /><br />Apple's totalitarian approach of controlling the software and hardware now seems to be an admirable strategy. Microsoft's l<strike>ackluster</strike> <strike>disastrous</strike> <strike>ill-advised</strike>
release of Windows Vista and the subsequent torrent of software and
hardware incompatibilities (not to mention security holes) makes me
truly enjoy my Mac and its utter lack of headaches.<br /><br />http://www.psystar.com/index.php?&amp;page=shop.product_details&amp;flypage=flypage_images.tpl&amp;product_id=1&amp;category_id=3&amp;option=com_virtuemart&amp;Itemid=72 ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Gives new meaning to ejecting floppy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2008/04/gives-new-meaning-to-ejecting.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008://1.289</id>

    <published>2008-04-15T23:17:28Z</published>
    <updated>2008-04-15T23:34:11Z</updated>

    <summary>A pretty bizarre article on the BBC&apos;s Technology section discusses future human-robot relations as machines grow more capable and &quot;intelligent.&quot;The major focus on the article is David Levy, author of &quot;Love + Sex with Robots&quot; - a fairly adroit book...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Technology" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="technology" label="technology" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><a href="http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/data-tasha.html" onclick="window.open('http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/data-tasha.html','popup','width=507,height=417,scrollbars=no,resizable=no,toolbar=no,directories=no,location=no,menubar=no,status=no,left=0,top=0'); return false"><img src="http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/data-tasha-thumb-250x205.jpg" width="250" height="205" alt="data-tasha.jpg" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></a></span>A pretty bizarre article on the BBC's Technology section discusses future human-robot relations as machines grow more capable and "intelligent."<div><br /></div><div>The major focus on the article is David Levy, author of "Love + Sex with Robots" - a fairly adroit book title - who feels that intimate relations with intelligent robots are a natural evolutionary track. </div><div><br /></div><div>The captions on the included photos are pretty amusing, "Can we ever form meaningful relationships with robots?" included under a picture of a humanoid robot, wires exposed, either balancing a soccer ball, or getting hit by one, and another photo with the caption "Could robots replicate the complexity of human relationships?" and that photo shows, well, certain complexities of human relationships. </div><div><br /></div><div>As far-fetched a concept as this is, sadly I can say that I've encountered some curiously suspicious IT types in my day who I can see taking full advantage of the possibility of programming a mate. Actually doesn't seem that bad of an idea once you say it...</div><div><br /></div><div>To some degree society has already primed us for such possibilities, with The Stepford Wives and of course the fembots from the thirty-seven Austin Powers films.</div><div><br /></div>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Guess who&apos;s coming (Back) to dinner?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2008/04/guess-whos-coming-back-to-dinn.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008://1.288</id>

    <published>2008-04-15T14:37:35Z</published>
    <updated>2008-04-15T15:18:34Z</updated>

    <summary> Like the dinner guest you never invited, Silvio Berlusconi has returned to office in Italy, his party winning a majority in the Italian government. Italy, as I have stated ad nauseum, is in desperate need of reform. Berlusconi is...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Economics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="International" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="development" label="development" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="italy" label="Italy" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="palazzochigi" label="Palazzo Chigi" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="politics" label="politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="silvioberlusconi" label="Silvio Berlusconi" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[<div align="center"><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><a href="http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/DSC00028-780221.html" onclick="window.open('http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/DSC00028-780221.html','popup','width=1024,height=768,scrollbars=no,resizable=no,toolbar=no,directories=no,location=no,menubar=no,status=no,left=0,top=0'); return false"><img src="http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/DSC00028-780221-thumb-500x375.jpg" alt="silvio_berlusconi_2008.JPG" class="mt-image-left" style="margin: 0pt 20px 20px 0pt; float: left;" height="375" width="500" /></a></span></div>
Like the dinner guest you never invited, Silvio Berlusconi has returned to office in Italy, his party winning a majority in the Italian government. Italy, as I have stated ad nauseum, is in desperate need of reform. Berlusconi is not the man for the job. While a wildly successful billionaire businessman, Berlusconi is best known in the political arena for his cafone-like outbursts that place Italy in diplomatic gaffes. Here are some of his "best" quotes:<br /><ul><li>
<font size="2">
"I am the Jesus Christ of politics. I am a patient victim, I put up with everyone, I sacrifice myself for everyone."</font></li><li><font size="2">
"I will try to meet your expectations, and I promise from now on,
two-and-a-half months of absolute sexual abstinence, until [election
day on] 9 April."</font></li><li><font size="2">(To German MEP Martin Schulz, at start of Italy's EU presidency in July 2003)<b>:</b>
<p>
"I know that in Italy there is a man producing a film on Nazi
concentration camps - I shall put you forward for the role of Kapo
(guard chosen from among the prisoners) - you would be perfect."</p></font></li><li><font size="2">
"Let's talk about football and women." (Turning to four-times-married
German Chancellor, Gerhard Schroeder.) "Gerhard, why don't you start?"</font></li><li><font size="2">
"Italy is now a great country to invest in... today we have fewer
communists and those who are still there deny having been one. Another
reason to invest in Italy is that we have beautiful secretaries...
superb girls."</font></li><li><font size="2">
"Mussolini never killed anyone. Mussolini used to send people on vacation in internal </font>
<font size="2">exile."</font></li><li><font size="2"><p>
"We must be aware of the superiority of our civilisation, a system that
has guaranteed well-being, respect for human rights and - in contrast
with Islamic countries - respect for religious and political rights, a
system that has as its value understanding of diversity and
tolerance... </p><p>
"The West will continue to conquer peoples, even if it means a
confrontation with another civilisation, Islam, firmly entrenched where
it was 1,400 years ago." </p></font></li><li>
<font size="2">

"There is no-one on the world stage who can compete with me."</font></li><li><font size="2">(On a proposal to base an EU food standards agency in Finland, rather than the Italian city of Parma):
<p>

"Parma is synonymous with good cuisine. The Finns don't even know what prosciutto is. I cannot accept this."</p></font></li></ul>Some interesting press headlines from major news outlets show just how unenthusiastic 
Berlusconi's re-election was:<br /><br />International Herald Tribune: <br /><h1 class="headline">Economy ailing, frustrated Italy picks Berlusconi</h1><br />
CNN:<br /><h1 class="headline">Italian Billionaire Berlusconi 'wins' election</h1>
<br />The Independent:<br /><h1 class="headline">Disillusioned Italians head to polls again</h1><br />Reuters:<br />
<h1 class="headline">Giving it to Berlusconi</h1><br />and lastly Reuters columnist Robin Pomeroy:<br /><h1 class="headline">"Irreplaceable" Berlusconi set to "save" Italy</h1><br />
Since Berlusconi spent much of his last run at PM pushing laws to give himself immunity from prosecution, perhaps he will have enough free time now to actually push through some changes. But most likely it will be the same old <i>merda</i>.<br /><br />(The text on the picture above is Italian for "beware of dog.")<br />
<br />
<br /><br /> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The road not taken</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2008/04/the-road-not-taken.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008://1.287</id>

    <published>2008-04-15T13:50:14Z</published>
    <updated>2008-04-15T14:08:46Z</updated>

    <summary><![CDATA[Amnesty International recently released a damming report on the death penalty worldwide for 2006 this week, noting that the U.S. has the ignoble seat at the table of the top six countries most frequently performing capital punishment.&nbsp;Here are some key...]]></summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="America" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="america" label="America" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="crime" label="crime" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="deathpenalty" label="death penalty" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="humanrights" label="human rights" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="politics" label="politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[Amnesty International recently released a damming report on the death penalty worldwide for 2006 this week, noting that the U.S. has the ignoble seat at the table of the top six countries most frequently performing capital punishment.&nbsp;<br /><br />Here are some key facts taken from Amnesty's report:<br /><ul><li>91 per cent of
all known executions took place in six countries: China, Iran,
Pakistan, Iraq, Sudan and the USA.</li><li>Some estimates say China executed at least 1,010 people, although Amnesty notes credible sources suggest
that between 7,500 to 8,000 were executed.</li><li>
Iran executed 177 people, <br /></li><li>Pakistan executed 82,</li><li>Iraq executed at least 65,<br /></li><li>Sudan executed at least 65, and<br /></li><li>There were 53 executions in 12 states in the USA.</li></ul>Given that no major study shows that the death penalty acts as a deterrent for crime, that all developed nations with the exceptions of South Korea and Singapore have all abolished the death penalty for this same reason - how is it we can proclaim ourselves leaders in all things humanitarian and still allow ourselves to sit in league with the most atrocious abusers of human rights on the planet? Lets separate logic from our sympathy for victims. What is the macro effect capital punishment is having on our society?<br /><br />Note: this is a continuing thread of death penalty coverage, for more, click below:<br /><br /><a href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2005/10/the-death-penalty-an-update.html">The death penalty - an update</a><br /><br /><a href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2004/12/romney-wouldbe-executioner.html">Romney - would-be executioner</a><br /><br /><a href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2004/11/canadas-embrace-of-progressive.html">Canada's embrace of progressives</a><br /><br /><a href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2003/01/kerry-massachusetts-is-your-st.html">Kerry, Massachusetts is your strength</a><br /><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Italy votes, again (so soon?)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2008/04/italy-votes-again-so-soon.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008://1.286</id>

    <published>2008-04-14T13:11:51Z</published>
    <updated>2008-04-15T14:26:26Z</updated>

    <summary> Yet another election is at hand for Italy&apos;s top spot. Italian voters have two days at the polls to decide who should take the Prime Minister&apos;s job - Walter Veltroni, center-left candidate and former Mayor of Rome, or Silvio...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Economics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="International" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="chamberofdeputies" label="Chamber of Deputies" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="development" label="development" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="europe" label="Europe" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="europeanunion" label="European Union" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="italiansenate" label="Italian Senate" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="italy" label="Italy" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="politics" label="politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Prodi-Poll.jpg" src="http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/13italy-sub550.jpg" class="mt-image-center" style="margin: 0pt auto 20px; text-align: center; display: block;" height="320" width="550" /></span> <div>Yet another election is at hand for Italy's top spot. Italian voters have two days at the polls to decide who should take the Prime Minister's job - Walter Veltroni, center-left candidate and former Mayor of Rome, or Silvio Berlusconi, center-right candidate, twice former Prime Minister and successful businessman. Berlusconi had two chances to improve Italy's lot and did little to nothing. Italy is the slowest growing major European economy and by most accounts was just passed by Spain in per capita income. This will be Italy's 63rd government since the end of World War II.</div><div><br /></div><div>The country needs major economic and political reforms for it to keep pace with the Eurozone. The country has one of the most regulated and&nbsp;bureaucratic&nbsp;systems of developed nations and business and proper employment struggle under the weight.</div><div><br /></div><div>Compared with Berlusconi, Veltroni is easily my candidate of choice, however, it is very unclear whether he has the forza or intensita to make the changes that are needed. Departing Prime Minister Romano Prodi (pictured above) was hailed as the right man for the job when he took office two years ago, however, his administration was plagued by in-fighting and fractures that ultimately unwound his governing coalition. Seats in Italy's Camera dei Deputati seem to award a disproportionate share to minority and fringe parties, forcing the larger ones to make "deals with the devil" in order to form a governing coalition. While at first glance it provides a more equal voice to all perspectives, it is entirely unpractical for proper governance.&nbsp;</div><div><br /></div><div>Veltroni, some 20 years younger than Berlusconi, has taken cues from U.S. presidential candidate Barak Obama, even adopting his catch phrase, "Yes we can!"</div><div><br /></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style: italic;">Ma può?</span></div>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Istria - sacrificial lamb for European peace</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2008/04/istria-sacrificial-lamb-for-eu.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008://1.284</id>

    <published>2008-04-09T15:38:54Z</published>
    <updated>2008-04-09T17:00:25Z</updated>

    <summary>Qui si fa l&apos;Italia o si muore. (Today we&apos;ll unite Italy, or die trying). - Giuseppe Garibaldi, May 15, 1860Many people outside of Italy have never heard of Istria. To most it may sound like a fictional place. Istria is...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="International" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="austrohungarianempire" label="Austro-Hungarian Empire" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="croatia" label="Croatia" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="europe" label="Europe" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="europeanunion" label="European Union" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="italy" label="Italy" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="romanempire" label="Roman Empire" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="rome" label="Rome" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="slovenia" label="Slovenia" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="yugoslavia" label="Yugoslavia" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><a href="http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/Cartaistria.html" onclick="window.open('http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/Cartaistria.html','popup','width=800,height=1043,scrollbars=no,resizable=no,toolbar=no,directories=no,location=no,menubar=no,status=no,left=0,top=0'); return false"><img src="http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/Cartaistria-thumb-150x195.jpg" alt="Cartaistria.jpg" class="mt-image-left" style="margin: 0pt 20px 20px 0pt; float: left;" height="195" width="150" /></a></span><i>Qui si fa l'Italia o si muore</i>. (Today we'll unite Italy, or die trying). - Giuseppe Garibaldi, May 15, 1860<br /><br />Many people outside of Italy have never heard of Istria. To most it may sound like a fictional place. Istria is the Mediterranean's largest peninsula, located in the Adriatic sea, east of Venice, at the base of the Julian Alps. It first came under Italian domination after the area was Romanized in 177 BC. It remained either under Italian (via Venice) rule or Italian influence solidly through the Treaty of Campo Formio in 1797, in which Napoleon (occupier of Italy) ceded it to Austria in exchange for Mediterranean possessions. The period of&nbsp; Austrian rule, roughly from 1797 to  1918, correlated directly with the rise of the Italian unification movement (Italy since the fall of the western Roman Empire in 476 had been divided into various entities). The Austrians ruled over areas that were rightfully Italian and thus sought to complicate and block Italian efforts of reuniting the country. One of their most devious efforts was to dilute the Italian population by importing Slovenes and Croats from other parts of their empire.<br /><br />Charles Upton Clark, in the New York Times December 23, 1917 wrote, "<i>Austria then, has had just a century in which to win Istrian allegiance; and she has made use of every device known to the Teuton. By wholesale importation she has made the countryside Slav; but Italians still pay five-sixths of the rent tax, four-fifths of the income tax. She gives subventions to some fifty-five Croatian schools-those of Sts. Cyril and Methodius - but that it is purely missionary work is shown by the fact that Istrians contribute only about 10 percent of the receipts; the rest is supplied by the Government and private and clerical contributions from Croatia. Austria has filled Istria with German and Slav civil, military, and naval employees; in Pola, for instance, in the 1912 elections, only 1 per cent of the navy vote was for the Italian candidate. Italians, then, are as justified in feeling sympathy for their Istrian brethren as do the French for the Alsatians.</i>"<br /><br />Clark wrote further, "<i>Historically, then, Istria is a segment of unredeemed Italy. Geographically, she is as truly Italian. Italy is bounded by the Alps and the three seas; and the Julian Alps swing across the base of Istria, divide it off from the Slav hinterland, and give it, by their protection, a Mediterranean climate, with the olive groves and the vineyards so characteristic of Italy."</i><br /><br />Finally, at the conclusion of the First World War, Istria was given to Italy. However this would not last long, the short-sighted Italian governments of the postwar era became dominated by the fascists, who sought to undo the Austrian wrong by a forced Italianization of the recent Slav immigrants. It became forbidden to teach, worship, or conduct business in any other language than Italian. At the conclusion of the Second World War, with Italy surrendering to the allies, Istria was first occupied by the British, who handed control over to the Yugoslav Communist partisans. In the ensuing weeks, the partisans rounded up and executed Italians in what became known as the "foibe massacres."<br /><br /><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><a href="http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/Istria_census_1910.html" onclick="window.open('http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/Istria_census_1910.html','popup','width=780,height=961,scrollbars=no,resizable=no,toolbar=no,directories=no,location=no,menubar=no,status=no,left=0,top=0'); return false"><img src="http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/Istria_census_1910-thumb-150x184.png" alt="Istria_census_1910.PNG" class="mt-image-left" style="margin: 0pt 20px 20px 0pt; float: left;" height="184" width="150" /></a></span>Yugoslav troops remained in control of Istria until the territory was formally awarded to it piecemeal over several treaties. <br /><br />The population of Istria at the time, largely Italian, began a large-scale exodus to Italy proper, resulting of the peninsula losing approximately 80% of its inhabitants. The new&nbsp; Yugoslav Communist government quickly imported Slovenes, Croats, Bosnians, and Albanians to move into the houses and neighborhoods vacated by the native Italians. The situation was so desperate that the evacuating Italians took with them not only their belongings but also their dead. Some notable Istrians include race driver Mario Andretti, actress Alida Valli and Laura Antonelli, singer Sergio Endrigo, and boxer Nino Benvenuti.<br /><br /><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><a href="http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/Istria_ethnic2001.html" onclick="window.open('http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/Istria_ethnic2001.html','popup','width=410,height=288,scrollbars=no,resizable=no,toolbar=no,directories=no,location=no,menubar=no,status=no,left=0,top=0'); return false"><img src="http://lastoftheromans.org/assets/Istria_ethnic2001-thumb-150x105.png" alt="Istria_ethnic2001.png" class="mt-image-left" style="margin: 0pt 20px 20px 0pt; float: left;" height="105" width="150" /></a></span>Some have said there was a tacit agreement by the postwar Italian government and the new Yugoslav government whereby Italy agreed not to pursue the foibe massacres of Yugoslavia ceased its demand for the extradition of Italian fascist accused of war crimes. <br /><br />Though ethically questionable, this sort of approach worked reasonably well in keeping Europe largely stable through the post-war era and through the demise of the Cold War. Europe as a whole appears to have deliberately left matters of the past unsettled, waiting for the period's contemporaries to pass, the issues to die, in the hope that a continent permanently (perhaps fatally) compromised and castrated will create itself a new identity.<br /><br />My question is, will old animosities be reignited when wealthy Italians start buying up inexpensive properties in Istria now that Slovenia is an EU member and Croatia is on the candidate list? Will the Istrian towns once again be called by their proper Italian names?<br />]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Afflicting the comfortable</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2008/04/afflicting-the-comfortable.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008://1.283</id>

    <published>2008-04-08T18:07:57Z</published>
    <updated>2008-04-15T14:27:09Z</updated>

    <summary>Anyone else notice how closely the national press follows polls? Not coincidentally, national coverage of the Iraq war has taken a back seat to the election and the economy, which seems to be a direct reflection of national polling[1]. It&apos;s...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="America" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Economics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="International" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="america" label="America" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="crisis" label="crisis" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="economics" label="economics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="election2008" label="election 2008" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="georgebush" label="George Bush" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="imperialism" label="imperialism" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="iraq" label="Iraq" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="politics" label="politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="quagmire" label="quagmire" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[Anyone else notice how closely the national press follows polls? Not coincidentally, national coverage of the Iraq war has taken a back seat to the election and the economy, which seems to be a direct reflection of national polling[1]. <br /><br />It's commonly said that a good journalist constantly seeks to "afflict the comfortable" - that is to bring the most troubling issues of our time front and center to the least affected. While there are plenty of good journalists scouring the world reporting on some of the most horrid issues of our time, there is a terrible haze of disinterest amongst the American public for all things unpleasant. <br /><br />I don't propose this is anything new, but it seems to be more pronounced of late. <br /><br /><img src="http://lastoftheromans.org/bush460.jpg" align="center"><br /><br />It all speaks to the cultural failure to assume personal responsibility. If you voted for Bush in 2000, or 2004, you are part responsible for this mess we're in in Iraq.<br /><br /><i>Dear American Public,<br /><br />Remember when you voted for Bush (at least once), and were cheerleading the Iraq invasion? What have you been up to lately? Ignoring casualty counts? Changing the channel when the coverage of Iraq starts? Yeah, look, you can't have it both ways. Sack up, admit you made a mistake, and learn your lesson to be skeptical of leadership like the founding fathers intended.<br /><br />Oh, and lose some weight you fat bastard.<br /><br />Sincerely,<br /><br />Last of the Romans Management.<br /></i><br /><br />---<br />[1] http://www.pollingreport.com/prioriti.htm<br /> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Old habits die hard</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2008/01/old-habits-die-hard.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008://1.282</id>

    <published>2008-02-01T03:36:36Z</published>
    <updated>2008-04-15T14:27:38Z</updated>

    <summary>Ever-turbulent Italy has once again vomited its most recent government of Romano Prodi (pictured) in a no confidence vote. This represents the collapse of Italy&apos;s 61st government since the end of the 2nd World War. As much as we may...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="International" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="campania" label="Campania" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="italy" label="Italy" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="naples" label="Naples" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="palazzochigi" label="Palazzo Chigi" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="politics" label="politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="romanoprodi" label="Romano Prodi" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="silvioberlusconi" label="Silvio Berlusconi" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[<img src="blather/archives/prodi_new.jpg" align="center"><br>Ever-turbulent Italy has once again vomited its most recent government of Romano Prodi (pictured) in a no confidence vote. This represents the collapse of Italy's 61st government since the end of the 2nd World War. <br><br>

As much as we may gripe about the exclusion and single-mindedness of the American political parties, Italy is much the opposite. At current there are some 39 political parties holding seats in the Camera dei Deputati. They range from communists to xenophobes. Each government must set up delicate coalitions in order to create a governable majority. Prodi's was rooted in the center-left but involved communists. I believe his government was well intentioned but ultimately lacked the boldness needed to pass crucial reforms.<br><br>

Today Italy lags as the slowest growing member of the G8. According to some economists, Spain has now passed it in terms of GDP per capita. The south, not-so-affectionately referred to as the Mezzogiorno, is quite nearly another country; much poorer, much more rural, and with much more unemployment. Naples is awash in garbage; unions have refused to collect any additional trash because the Campanian dumps are overflowing. The EU is currently threatening Italy with penalties if it doesn't sort out the potential health disaster. Leadership is needed.<br><br>

What isn't needed, however, is a return of former Prime Minister Silvio Berlusconi. He's made remarks lately that indicate he wants to assume his old office a mere 20 months after being voted out. He spent the majority of his five year tenure making legal maneuvers to keep him from being prosecuted, neglecting the country's needed economic reforms. Italy today is one of the developed world's most heavily regulated economies.

Buona fortuna, Italia, you need it.]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Election &apos;08: Quo vadis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2008/01/election-08-quo-vadis.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2008://1.281</id>

    <published>2008-01-09T22:23:50Z</published>
    <updated>2008-01-27T22:28:16Z</updated>

    <summary>I consider myself a pretty decisive person, but when it comes to this election I am having a hard time deciding among the candidates. I supported Joe Biden, the Democratic Senator from Delaware because I thought he had the best...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="debt" label="debt" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="development" label="development" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="election2008" label="election 2008" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="foreignpolicy" label="foreign policy" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="growth" label="growth" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="politics" label="politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="taxes" label="taxes" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[I consider myself a pretty decisive person, but when it comes to this election I am having a hard time deciding among the candidates. I supported Joe Biden, the Democratic Senator from Delaware because I thought he had the best blend of pragmatism and experience. He didn't make it past Iowa and judging from the caucus results you'd wonder if he was even in Iowa. I suppose this election just catches me at a philosophical fork-in-the-road; I find myself becoming more and more alienated from the positions and behavior of the Democratic Party. Make no mistake, however, this doesn't also mean that I'm moving closer and closer to the Republican Party - trust me, far from that. I'm not sure where this puts me, personally it feels like I'm just moving off into the tall grass. <br><br>I've always been fiscally-oriented when it comes to politics; my personal perspective is that social issues should really be outside of the domain of legislators. Call me a Libertarian, but the Constitution didn't entrust Congress with the responsibility for deciding who can marry who or what type of family is best, or what religion I should subscribe to. I just want Congress to run the country and do it as efficiently as possible. That includes fixing Iraq, cutting waste and spending, and defending the borders and fixing immigration.<br><br>Currently there is no candidate that has any sort of record as a waste-cutter, who is detached enough from the party bases that could govern effectively, who would stick to matters of Government (and not personal matters), while at the same time improving our standing in the world and righting the federal budget.<br><br>It seems as well that this malaise that has paralyzed government extends to some extent to the state and local levels. I can tell you from experience that the near $5,000 a year I pay in property taxes seems to buy me only really expensive garbagemen and <a href="http://www.myrevere.net/default.asp?sourceid=&amp;smenu=1&amp;twindow=&amp;mad=&amp;sdetail=5206&amp;wpage=1&amp;skeyword=&amp;sidate=&amp;ccat=&amp;ccatm=&amp;restate=&amp;restatus=&amp;reoption=&amp;retype=&amp;repmin=&amp;repmax=&amp;rebed=&amp;rebath=&amp;subname=&amp;pform=&amp;sc=1359&amp;hn=myrevere&amp;he=.net">police who get their cars stolen from in front of the police station</a>. I think I want a refund.<br>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Uocchie</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2007/12/uocchie.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2007://1.280</id>

    <published>2007-12-07T03:38:16Z</published>
    <updated>2008-01-27T22:28:16Z</updated>

    <summary> The embedded song &quot;Uocchie&quot; or &quot;Eyes&quot; was the winner of Amnesty International&apos;s 2005 Voices of Liberty artistic competition. It was written and performed by an Italian neoroots band called Sancto Ianne. The band sings in Beneventano, a dialect hailing...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="crisis" label="crisis" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="italy" label="Italy" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="refugees" label="refugees" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[<object width="425" height="355"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/7sN69rmTeiY&rel=1"></param><param name="wmode" value="transparent"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/7sN69rmTeiY&rel=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" wmode="transparent" width="425" height="355"></embed></object><br><br>

The embedded song "Uocchie" or "Eyes" was the winner of Amnesty International's 2005 Voices of Liberty artistic competition. It was written and performed by an Italian neoroots band called Sancto Ianne. The band sings in Beneventano, a dialect hailing from - you guessed it - Benevento, in Campania. The song, from what little I can understand of it, is about the plight of refugees in the world.<Br><Br> Also appearing in the song and singing parts in Arabic, is Palestinian artist Faisal Taher.

The closing lines, if I understand them remotely correctly read:<br><Br>

<i>E rancichi cu ll'ogne chillu mare<br>
Fin'a che quacche cosa nun cumpare<br>
Na terra, na furtuna, n'ato munno<br>
Che diciarra ca pure tu si n'ommo.</i> <Br><br>

And ever desperate over sea<br>
That which they seek does not appear<br>
No land, no wealth, an idle world<br>
That says you are not a man<br>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Throwing Romney from the train</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2007/12/throwing-romney-from-the-train-1.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2007://1.279</id>

    <published>2007-12-07T02:26:32Z</published>
    <updated>2008-01-27T22:28:15Z</updated>

    <summary>Mitt Romney gave his anticipated speech today on his Mormon faith and how that plays into his run for president. Every media outlet has been comparing it with JFK’s famous 1960 speech about Catholicism. In fact they were wildly different...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="America" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="america" label="America" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="election2008" label="election 2008" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="politics" label="politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="religion" label="religion" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="separationofchurchandstate" label="separation of church and state" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[Mitt Romney gave his anticipated speech today on his Mormon faith and how that plays into his run for president. Every media outlet has been comparing it with JFK’s famous 1960 speech about Catholicism. In fact they were wildly different speeches. Romney sought to cozy up to evangelicals while Kennedy sought to distance himself from influence from the Vatican. Compare these two quotes:<br><br>

Kennedy: “I believe in an America where religious intolerance will someday end; where all men and all churches are treated as equal; where every man has the same right to attend or not attend the church of his choice…”<br><br>

Romney: “But in recent years, the notion of the separation of church and state has been taken by some well beyond its original meaning. They seek to remove from the public domain any acknowledgment of God. Religion is seen as merely a private affair with no place in public life. It is as if they are intent on establishing a new religion in America – the religion of secularism. They are wrong. “<br><br>

Quite contrary to the spirit of the JFK speech, but the two were clearly catering to distinct interests.]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Plus ça change?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2007/08/plus-ca-change.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2007://1.278</id>

    <published>2007-08-30T21:06:18Z</published>
    <updated>2008-01-27T22:28:15Z</updated>

    <summary>Aesthe.nu is back online as Last of the Romans.org. It&apos;s been a long time coming (a year and a half?) but now the wheels are turning again.Quick summary of the past year and a half: Republicans trounced in national elections,...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
    <category term="america" label="America" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="development" label="development" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="economics" label="economics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="employment" label="employment" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="growth" label="growth" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="life" label="life" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="massachusetts" label="Massachusetts" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="revere" label="Revere" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[Aesthe.nu is back online as Last of the Romans.org. It's been a long time coming (a year and a half?) but now the wheels are turning again.<BR><BR>Quick summary of the past year and a half: Republicans trounced in national elections, congressional and senatorial majorities wiped out, but I'm not entirely impressed with the new Democratic leadership either. Harry Reid has as much charisma as an elderly woman complaining about the price of soup. It's nice to see both a woman and an Italian-American in a position of leadership in the House of Representatives in Nancy Pelosi. She hasn't shot her own foot off either yet, which is encouraging. <BR><BR>The housing market seems a bit like the homeless man that cans at the corner of North Washington and Causeway streets in Boston. He has the ability to sleep standing up, while holding a sign, but sometimes slowly tips over to the point where you're not sure if he's going to fall or not. This market seems to be in a similar position, teetering on the brink of utter deflation, especially considering the amount of foreclosures that are going to be putting homes on the market (and people out of homes)... not good for those relying on equity or planning to sell. <BR><BR>Some of this could have been prevented by increased regulation in the lending industry to eliminate the predatory lending practices that have nearly bankrupted 2 million Americans.<BR><BR>In local developments: Is the renaissance of Revere at hand? Two major projects will be breaking ground over the next year along the Boulevard, the &lt;a href="http://www.liveatoceanclub.com&gt;Ocean Club&lt;/a&gt; and the Waterfront Square project to develop Parcel H near Wonderland T station. Both are very aggressive by Revere standards: Ocean Club would place a massive development of upscale lofts along an undeveloped and overgrown stretch of the beach, including a pool and a massive amenity area (for residents). The nicest units are selling for over $1 million. Waterfront Square is a very aggressive mixed-use proposal that would sit on 10 acres next to Wonderland station (the northern terminus of the blue line subway) including a 13-story hotel, 902 condominiums, and 200,000 square feet of office, restaurant and retail space. It was written up by the Boston Globe today&nbsp;<A href="http://www.boston.com/business/articles/2007/08/30/development_likely_to_have_revere_beach_gleaming_anew/">here</A>. Maybe things are looking up.<BR>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Debt Desperados</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://lastoftheromans.org/2006/05/debt-desperados.html" />
    <id>tag:lastoftheromans.org,2006://1.277</id>

    <published>2006-05-17T03:39:47Z</published>
    <updated>2008-01-27T22:28:15Z</updated>

    <summary>Fidelity&apos;s Stages investing newsletter profiled Jordan Goodman, author of Master Your Money Type: Using Your Financial Personality to Create a Life of Wealth and Freedom. His six &quot;money types&quot; are: Strivers have energy and drive and make great entrepreneurs, but...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nick DeLena</name>
        <uri>http://lastoftheromans.org</uri>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Economics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="debt" label="debt" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="finance" label="finance" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="growth" label="growth" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="investment" label="investment" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="savings" label="savings" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://lastoftheromans.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Fidelity's <i>Stages</i> investing newsletter profiled Jordan Goodman, author of <i>Master Your Money Type: Using Your Financial Personality to Create a Life of Wealth and Freedom</i>. His six "money types" are:<br />
<blockquote><br />
<strong>Strivers</strong> have energy and drive and make great entrepreneurs, but they can get into trouble when their spending and lifestyle get ahead of their earnings.<br />
<strong>Ostriches</strong> say they're baffled by money, even while they succeed in a variety of professions. Some Ostriches are White Knighters, waiting for a "white knight" (an unexpected inheritance, for example) to rescue them from money problems.<br />
<strong>Debt Desperados</strong> are always coming up short because of overspending or being underfinanced. These are the folks who spiral downward, creating more debt by borrowing to pay previous debt.<br />
<strong>Coasters</strong> are organized, responsible and stable - but often too complacent, letting opportunities slip through their fingers. Although Coasters are doing fine, Goodman cautions, standing still can be riskier than they think.<br />
<strong>High Rollers</strong> will be found gambling around a table, staking everything on a dream to build a business, or playing the stock market on margin. With proper planning, though, their energy and tenacity can win the day, according to Goodman.<br />
<strong>Squirrels</strong> secretly fear losing everything. No matter how much they've accumulated, it isn't enough, and they risk becoming hoarders who never enjoy their wealth. "Squirrels deserve to enjoy their money now," says Goodman.</blockquote></p>

<p>I'm pretty confident I fall under the "strivers" category... while the federal government falls under the "debt desperados" category. How amusing.</p>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

</feed>
